Stormy Ramsey | Full Stack Web Developer

Washington, DC | 202.294.5212 stormy.ramsey@gmail.com stormyramsey.github.io

As a Web Developer I am passionate about using my technology skills to create the best user experience for clients. I enjoy finding creative and effective ways to bring designer's concepts to life and making their websites easily accessible through responsive design.

SKILLS

- Git and Github
- Bootstrap
- Ruby & Ruby on Rails
- AJAX

- Sinatra
- MEAN Stack
- ReactJS
- Adobe Creative Cloud

WORK EXPERIENCE

General Assembly Web Development Immersive Student

Washington, DC March 2017 – June 2017

- Participated in a full-time twelve-week full-stack web development immersive course, covering a variety of languages, front-and-back-end frameworks, focusing on industry best practices in Object-Oriented Programming, MVC Frameworks, Data Modeling, and Test-Driven Development.
- In this program, I built multiple applications using: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Ruby on Rails, Active Record, PostgreSQL, SQL, AJAX, APIs, JSON, RESTful routes, MEAN Stack (MongoDB, ExpressJS, AngularJS, Node.js), Bash Shell Scripting, Git, GitHub, and Heroku.

Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board Executive Assistant

77 K Street NE, Washington, DC 4/2015 – 3/2017

- Coordinated travel arrangements and contract payments; updated and maintained office business operations.
- Managed SharePoint website, monitor task through SharePoint central administration.
- Demonstrated technology to business units, training materials and SharePoint resources.

Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board Correspondence Analyst

77 K Street NE, Washington, DC 11/2013 - Present

• Responsible for analyzing, evaluating, reviewing, processing, routing and tracking incoming and outgoing correspondences for the Thrift Savings Plan.

U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, SAMHSA Administrative Support Assistant (Office Automation) GS-06

1 Choke Cherry Rd. Rockville, MD 12/2012 – 11/2013

 Provided administrative support for office staff. Maintain the Division Director's calendar and schedule meetings with internal staff as well as outside entities.

Stormy Ramsey | Web Developer

Washington, DC | 202.294.5212 stormy.ramsey@gmail.com stormyramsey.github.io

U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, ACF Information Technology Management Assistant

901 D Street SW, Washington, DC 7/2012 – 9/2012

- Web Development Developed websites for agency's intranet utilizing HTML and CSS3.
- Web Management Responsible for managing the agency's website using web publishing tools such as HTML 5 and CSS3.
- Section 508 Compliance Assignment Responsible for reviewing PDF files using Adobe Acrobat, for accessibility and making any corrections to documents for them to follow Section 508 regulations.
- Special Assignments Responsible for redeveloping and simplifying the agency's email listing help desk (listserv) which now enables users to execute issues on their own by following a step by step troubleshooting guide.

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Web Development Immersive Bootcamp

Northern Virginia Community College Web Design

The Art Institute of Fort Lauderdale Video Production Summa Cum Laude

Community College of Philadelphia Music Technology

Washington, DC Web Development Certificate 2017

Arlington, VA Certificate Program 2015

Fort Lauderdale, FL Associate of Science Degree Completed 2007

> Philadelphia, PA Credits earned for transfer 2004 – 2012